<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DocDock Documentation</title>
    <link>/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DocDock Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 09:07:20 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Terminal</title>
      <link>/programming/terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 18:01:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/programming/terminal/</guid>
      <description>Some useful terminal commands mkdir dir_name # Make Directory rm -r dir_name # Recursively remove content of a directory mv file1 dir1/ # move file1 to dir1 wget -O dir/file.ext url # download the file from url and save it in dir with filename file.ext wget url -P dir # download the file from url as save it in dir unzip file.zip #to unzip a file touch file_name.ext # create a new file open -a app_name file_name # open file using a specific application Accessing terminal command history Press Ctrl + R to enter the command history mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim</title>
      <link>/programming/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 10:51:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/programming/vim/</guid>
      <description>CAUTION It is strictly advised not to use vim if one is not a pro programmer. One is most likely to waste a lot of time doing simple stuffs on vim. This guide is meant as a basic starting point to browse through files, make some small changes using terminal and vim. For programming the best IDE in my opinion is VS Code.
Basic Editing with Vim Vim is a powerful text editor designed in such a manner such that one has to never leave the keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Website using Hugo and Github</title>
      <link>/programming/creating_website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 08:45:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/programming/creating_website/</guid>
      <description>I was long looking for a hugo theme where I could organize my content in a tree directory structure. I finally found the one that I am currently using.
The theme is named the-roots-home. The link to its gihub repo is https://github.com/rmsubekti/the-roots-home
In order to learn how to actually publish contents, I used the tutorial here https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LIFvgrRxdt4
To compile and view the site locally run
hugo server Publishing Contents Once content has been added its time to public them on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
